In this American English pronunciation video, we're going to study how to make the T and D consonant sounds.
在这段美式英语发音视频中，我们将学习如何发出 T 和 D 辅音音。
These two sounds are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
这两个音被放在一起是因为它们的口腔位置相同。
Tt is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth, and dd is voiced, meaning dd.
T 是无声的，意味着只有空气通过口腔，而 D 是有声的，意味着发出声音。
You make a sound with the vocal cords.
你用声带发出声音。
These consonants are complicated because the way Americans pronounce them isn't always what you'll find in a dictionary.
这些辅音很复杂，因为美国人发音的方式并不总是你在字典中找到的那样。
First, let's talk about the true pronunciation.
首先，让我们谈谈真正的发音。
These are stop consonants, which means there are two parts.
这些是爆破音，这意味着有两个部分。
First, a stop in the airflow, and second, a release.
首先是气流的阻断，其次是释放。
We stop here by closing the vocal cords, and lift the tongue so the flat, top part is at the roof of the mouth.
我们通过闭合声带来阻断气流，并抬起舌头，使平坦的顶部部分在口腔的顶部。
It's far forward, almost touching the back of the top front teeth.
它的位置很靠前，几乎接触到上前牙的后面。
The teeth come together, and we release all three parts at once.
牙齿合拢，我们同时释放所有三个部分。
The tongue comes down from the roof of the mouth, the teeth part, and we release the air in the throat.
舌头从口腔顶部下来，牙齿分开，我们在喉咙中释放空气。
Tt, dd.
Just like with other stop consonants, we want to release them into the next sound.
就像其他爆破音一样，我们希望将它们释放到下一个音中。
Let's look at the true T and D consonants up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察真正的 T 和 D 辅音。
The air stops in the throat, then the teeth part and the tongue pulls down to release.
空气在喉咙中停止，然后牙齿分开，舌头下拉释放。
The word desk.
单词 desk。
The teeth close and the tongue is at the roof of the mouth.
牙齿合拢，舌头在口腔顶部。
Then everything releases right into the EH as in bed vowel.
然后一切释放到 EH 音中，就像 bed 中的元音。
The word stick.
单词 stick。
The teeth close and the tongue is at the roof of the mouth.
牙齿合拢，舌头在口腔顶部。
Then everything releases right into the IH as in sit vowel.
然后一切释放到 IH 音中，就像 sit 中的元音。
The word expect.
单词 expect。
The teeth nearly close and the tongue is at the roof of the mouth.
牙齿几乎合拢，舌头在口腔顶部。
Then the teeth release just a bit.
然后牙齿稍微释放。
There's no next sound to release into, so the movement is minimal for the release.
没有下一个音可以释放，所以释放的动作很小。
The tongue releases down.
舌头向下释放。
It's possible to make the true D without the teeth coming together.
可以在不让牙齿合拢的情况下发出真正的 D 音。
Said, dd, dd.
Because of the voice in this sound, we can still release it.
由于这个音是有声的，我们仍然可以释放它。
Said, dd.
But to make the true T, the teeth do have to come together or nearly together.
但要发出真正的 T 音，牙齿必须合拢或几乎合拢。
Set, tt, tt.
That was the true T and true D.
那是真正的 T 和真正的 D。
If the T or D are at the end of a sentence, or if the next word begins with a consonant, then we make a stop T or stop D.
如果 T 或 D 在句子的末尾，或者下一个单词以辅音开头，那么我们发出停顿 T 或停顿 D。
We stop the air, but we don't release it.
我们阻止空气，但不释放它。
You lift your tongue into position, stop the air, and that's it.
你将舌头抬到位，阻止空气，仅此而已。
For example, the word mad.
例如，单词 mad。
Mad.
Notice the last sound is, dd, dd, the beginning of the D, dd, dd, with the vocal cords engaged because it's a voiced consonant.
注意最后的音是 dd, dd，是 D 的开始，dd, dd，因为它是有声辅音，声带参与。
And that's all.
就是这样。
I don't release.
我不释放。
A release would sound like this, mad, dd.
释放会听起来像这样，mad, dd。
But instead, I say mad, dd, leaving my tongue tip up.
但相反，我说 mad, dd，舌尖保持上抬。
Now let's look at an example with a T followed by another consonant, the phrase, not for me.
现在让我们看一个 T 后面跟着另一个辅音的例子，短语 not for me。
Here the T is followed by F.
这里 T 后面是 F。
I stop the air, not, and then without releasing, go into the F sound.
我阻止空气，not，然后不释放，进入 F 音。
Not for.
Not for me.
With stop consonants, we do stop the air in the throat.
对于停顿辅音，我们确实在喉咙中阻止空气。
So I don't have to move my tongue up into position for the T to stop the sound.
所以我不必将舌头抬到 T 的位置来阻止声音。
In this phrase, not for me, I touch the roof of my mouth with a part of the tongue that's further back.
在这个短语中，not for me，我用舌头更靠后的部分接触口腔顶部。
Not.
My tongue tip can stay down.
我的舌尖可以保持下垂。
This helps me make the stop even shorter, so I can quickly go into the next sound.
这帮助我使停顿更短，以便我可以快速进入下一个音。
Not for.
I'll bring my tongue up for the stop T if the next sound also requires the tongue being at the roof of the mouth.
如果下一个音也需要舌头在口腔顶部，我会将舌头抬起以发出停顿 T。
When I say, not for me, instead of, not for me, the words are more connected and the sentence is smoother.
当我说 not for me 而不是 not for me 时，单词更连贯，句子更流畅。
That's what we want in American English, and that's why we use the stop T instead of the true T in these cases.
这就是我们在美式英语中想要的，这也是为什么在这些情况下我们使用停顿 T 而不是真正的 T。
Not for me.
Let's look at a stop up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察一个停顿。
Here's the word, what.
这是单词 what。
I don't release the T at the end.
我不释放结尾的 T。
The tongue goes to the roof of the mouth.
舌头到达口腔顶部。
But then I just stop the air.
但然后我只是阻止空气。
My teeth aren't together, and I don't release.
我的牙齿没有合拢，我不释放。
The lips simply close.
嘴唇只是闭合。
What.
Here's what it looks like with a true T.
这是带有真正 T 的样子。
The teeth come together, then a subtle release.
牙齿合拢，然后微妙地释放。
Compare the ending.
比较结尾。
The top is what with a stop T, and the bottom is what with a true T.
上面是带有停顿 T 的 what，下面是带有真正 T 的 what。
For the stop T, the teeth don't come together because they don't need to release.
对于停顿 T，牙齿不合拢，因为它们不需要释放。
The air simply stops with the tongue in position.
空气只是随着舌头在位置上停止。
For the true T, we bring the teeth together so the tongue, teeth, and air release.
对于真正的 T，我们将牙齿合拢，以便舌头、牙齿和空气释放。
The stop T and D relate to the true T and D.
停顿 T 和 D 与真正的 T 和 D 相关。
We simply skip the release.
我们只是跳过释放。
But when the T or D come between two vowels or diphthongs, or after an R and before a vowel or diphthong, we make a different sound.
但当 T 或 D 位于两个元音或双元音之间，或在 R 之后和元音或双元音之前时，我们发出不同的声音。
One exception.
一个例外。
If the T or D starts a stressed syllable, then it's a true T or D.
如果 T 或 D 开始一个重读音节，那么它是一个真正的 T 或 D。
But in other cases, when the T or D consonants come between two vowels or diphthongs, or after an R and before a vowel or diphthong, we make a flap sound.
但在其他情况下，当 T 或 D 辅音位于两个元音或双元音之间，或在 R 之后和元音或双元音之前时，我们发出一个闪音。
This is different from the true and stop T and D because we don't stop the sound.
这与真正的和停顿的 T 和 D 不同，因为我们不停止声音。
We don't hold anything.
我们不保持任何东西。
We simply let the front part of the tongue bounce against the roof of the mouth without stopping the flow of air.
我们只是让舌头的前部在口腔顶部轻轻弹跳，而不停止气流。
The flap T and flap D sound the same.
闪音 T 和闪音 D 听起来一样。
The T in MATTER is the same as the D in MATTER.
MATTER 中的 T 和 MATTER 中的 D 是一样的。
MATTER.
MATTER。
This sounds just like the R in many languages.
这听起来就像许多语言中的 R。
But in American English, it's the flap T or flap D.
但在美式英语中，它是闪音 T 或闪音 D。
In my videos, I use the D symbol for this sound.
在我的视频中，我用 D 符号表示这个音。
This sound, however, isn't a stop consonant anymore.
然而，这个音不再是爆破音。
Let's look at some words with a flap up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察一些带有闪音的单词。
The word CITY.
单词 CITY。
Here, the T comes between two vowel sounds, so it's a flap.
这里，T 位于两个元音音之间，所以它是一个闪音。
The tongue is in position for the IH vowel.
舌头处于 IH 元音的位置。
Watch how it flaps the roof of the mouth quickly.
看它如何快速弹跳口腔顶部。
The air doesn't stop.
空气没有停止。
That flap was fast, even in slow motion.
即使在慢动作中，那个闪音也很快。
Let's watch again.
让我们再看一次。
The whole word one more time.
整个单词再看一次。
The word PARTY.
单词 PARTY。
Here, the T comes after an R and before a vowel, so it's a flap.
这里，T 位于 R 之后和元音之前，所以它是一个闪音。
The tongue is back and up for the R.
舌头向后并上抬以发 R 音。
Watch it flap.
看它如何弹跳。
And come down from the flap.
并从弹跳中下来。
The air didn't stop.
空气没有停止。
Watch the whole word one more time.
再看整个单词一次。
The word TIDY.
单词 TIDY。
Here, the D comes after a diphthong and before a vowel, so it's a flap D.
这里，D 位于双元音之后和元音之前，所以它是一个闪音 D。
Watch the tongue flap.
看舌头如何弹跳。
The whole word one more time.
整个单词再看一次。
Remember, this isn't represented in dictionaries.
记住，这在字典中没有表示。
They will show the symbol for the true T, PARTY, even though Americans pronounce it PARTY.
它们会显示真正的 T 符号，PARTY，即使美国人发音为 PARTY。
So remember the rule.
所以记住这个规则。
When a T or D comes between vowels and diphthongs, or after an R, before a vowel or diphthong, like PARTY, unless it starts a stressed syllable, flap the tongue.
当 T 或 D 位于元音和双元音之间，或在 R 之后，元音或双元音之前时，比如 PARTY，除非它开始一个重读音节，否则舌头弹跳。
Sometimes we drop the T or D completely.
有时我们完全省略 T 或 D。
We leave the sounds out.
我们省略这些音。
This is an American habit.
这是美国人的习惯。
If you look up the words in the dictionary, the sounds are there.
如果你在字典中查找这些单词，音是存在的。
There are two cases when you might hear an American word, drop a T or D.
有两种情况你可能会听到一个美国单词省略 T 或 D。
First, when the T or D comes between two consonant sounds.
首先，当 T 或 D 位于两个辅音音之间时。
For example, exactly.
例如，exactly。
This word has the K, T, L consonants together.
这个单词有 K, T, L 辅音在一起。
But most people pronounce it without the T.
但大多数人发音时省略 T。
Exactly.
Full pronunciation, exactly.
完整发音，exactly。
Common pronunciation, exactly.
常见发音，exactly。
Dropping the T between two consonants simplifies the pronunciation.
在两个辅音之间省略 T 简化了发音。
Also, we often drop the T when it comes after an N.
此外，当 T 位于 N 之后时，我们经常省略它。
Many Americans say center instead of center, or interview instead of interview.
许多美国人说 center 而不是 center，或 interview 而不是 interview。
This is a big topic.
这是一个大话题。
I have a whole series of videos on the pronunciation of T and D, which you can find on my website.
我有一整套关于 T 和 D 发音的视频系列，你可以在我的网站上找到。
Party, tidy.
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Best, tt, best.
Time, tt, time.
Do, dd.
Do.
Odd, dd.
Odd.
There's no way to make a Stop T sound on its own because it isn't a sound.
没有办法单独发出停顿 T 音，因为它不是一个音。
It's a lack of sound.
它是一个无声的状态。
Cut, cut.
Better, rr.